<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://egerou.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://egerou.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-05T10:36:55+00:00</updated><id>https://egerou.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why take time to write activity reports?</title><link href="https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/importance-of-reporting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why take time to write activity reports?"/><published>2024-12-06T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-06T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/importance-of-reporting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/importance-of-reporting/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to this blog post! I’d like to discuss the importance of public engagement activity reporting. Feel free to contact with your thoughts on the topic!</p> <p>I find that activity reporting is very important, but often is the first task to get pushed aside in time crunches. That’s why I’d like to talk more about why reporting is so important and why we should take care to do it well. As with any report, it’s important to keep in mind why it’s being written, and who will benefit from it. So let’s try to answer these questions!</p> <p>Here are a few answers I came up with:</p> <ul> <li>Gather all the information about the delivered workshop in a single place</li> </ul> <p>I like to make sure to include as many details as possible about the activity in its report. For example, I include the activity aims, objects, unfolding, and reflection. I find this helps me remember what really the activity was about when looking back at the report (for example when writing a grant proposal).</p> <p>As the name suggests, the document aims to report on the activity. That’s why I also include evaluation method, data, and analysis (charts, tables, …). Again, this can come in handy at a later time to showcase the impact of the activity. I feel reporting and evaluation go hand-in-hand, but let’s keep that topic for another blog-post!</p> <p>I’ve attached a template here for everyone to use, feel free to download it and adapt it to your needs. What would you change in the document?</p> <div class="download-container" style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; justify-content: center; align-items: center; text-align: center; margin-bottom: 20px;"> <div class="download-section">Activity Report Template</div> <a href="/assets/pdf/ActivityReport.odt" download=""> <i class="fas fa-file" style="font-size: 50px"></i> </a> </div> <ul> <li>Hear out every level of people involved in the activity</li> </ul> <p>As I briefly mentioned above, the report can be a place to reflect on the activity and how it went. I find it important that everyone linked to the activity gets a place to voice their opinion. That’s why I like to ask everyone from demonstrators, to event organizers, via funders and participants for their feedback. For example, I included a SWOT analysis section in the template above to gather everyone’s opinion. How do you make sure everyone is heard and feels valued?</p> <ul> <li>Learn from the activity and improve future ones</li> </ul> <p>After reflecting on the activity, I try to find ways to improve the activity. For example by answering: what parts should be discarded or improved? I aim to give ideas in the “Recommendation” section of the above template. These can be quite practical (give an extra 10 minutes here) or more broad (make sure to include oral explanations as well for this step). What do you pay attention to when reflecting on an activity?</p> <ul> <li>Showcase the impact of the activity</li> </ul> <p>This is more connected to “who” will read the report. Most often, funding agencies, higher-ups will want to make sure that their investments (time, financial, …) are worth it and require yearly reports for example. Activity reports can be a great way to showcase the success of the activity! Careful here because success can be measured in many ways. That’s why clearly defined objectives are important. For example, is a successful activity one that gets a good participants rating? Or one that trains many new demonstrators? What criteria do you use to measure an activity’s success?</p> <ul> <li>Help when writing funding applications</li> </ul> <p>To continue running workshops and activities, funding will eventually become a necessity. I find that having activity report ready can be of great help and inspiration when writing funding applications. For example, reports can help to show that the team is capable of delivering a successful activity and should continue to do so! Again, having everything in one place also makes the task easier. For example data might be ready available in the reports. How do you use activity reports when writing funding applications?</p> <ul> <li>Promote future activities</li> </ul> <p>I find that these activity reports can be very useful when advertising future activities. For example, I can use the data in the reports to showcase the success of previous activities which can suggest that this one will be great as well! Do you look through activity reports when advertising your next one?</p> <p>Overall, there are many reasons why we should take the time to write activity reports even during busy times. Why do <strong>you</strong> take the time to write activity reports? Send me an email to let me know!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="outreach"/><category term="reporting"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's talk about the importance of activity reporting!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Emilie’s PhD Research</title><link href="https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/phd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emilie’s PhD Research"/><published>2024-11-18T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/phd</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/phd/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to this blog post! I’d like to tell you a bit more about my PhD work and journey.</p> <p>During my PhD, I studied how I could use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyoxometalate">polyoxometalates</a> (or POMs for short - see the pictures below) to make better electronic memories.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Keggin polyoxometalate structure: central PO<sub>4</sub> group in yellow surrounded by 12 MoO<sub>3</sub> groups in blue. </div> <p>If reading isn’t quite your thing, you could have a look at this short video I made explaining my work!</p> <div style="position: relative; width: 100%;"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2OpVX-vuRoA" class="rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="100%" height="600" min-height="600"/> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> A short video about my PhD research. </div> <p>The issue with the current electronic memories we have is that they’re reaching their limits. We are continuously asking for faster, smaller, and more energy-efficient devices. Therefore, we need new types of electronics, and electronic memory devices. An example of an up and coming technology is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resistive_random-access_memory">resistive random access memories</a> (or RRAM for short). The main difference with the traditional transistor technology is that it only needs two electrodes, instead of the three. So, to make these RRAM devices, you simply sandwich a material of choice between two metal electrodes. In my case, I studied POMs as my material choice.</p> <p>Now, let me tell you more about POMs and why they’re great to make electronic memories. They are metal oxide nanoparticles, which means that they are made of metal and oxygen atoms, and are roughly 1 nm in size. Here are a few of their amazing properties:</p> <ul> <li>they can withstand a wide temperature range (-195 to 400 °C)</li> <li>they are soluble in many solvents even non-toxic and water based ones, which makes them very easy to process</li> <li>their structure is very easy to modify, and different chemical groups can be added to their base structure, therefore, it’s possible to tailor POMs properties to specific applications</li> <li>finally, most importantly, they can reversibly exchange multiple electrons with little structural change, meaning that different memory states can be stored via different number of electrons</li> </ul> <p>The last sentence is a bit tricky to understand, but very important. The help explain it better, we need to use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electrochemistry">electrochemistry</a>. When I say “<em>POMs can reversibly exchange multiple electrons</em>”, I mean that they have many redox states. And therefore, the different redox states of the POM are the different states of the memory device. The traditional transistors have two states: “on” and “off” or “1” and “0”. But with POMs, we could have many more states. This is very useful because it means that we can store more information in a single device, which is exactly what we want to make more efficient devices. Devices using this concept of storing multiple states in a single device using the material’s redox states are called <a href="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/celc.201300165">redox-based resistive random access memories</a> (or ReRAM for short).</p> <p>After talking about the material choice, the last point I’d like to discuss in this section, is the electrode choice. RRAM devices only need two electrodes, which can be arranged in different ways as shown in the image below. They can be either vertical (also called sandwich) or coplanar.</p> <div> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Electrodes-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Electrodes-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Electrodes-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Electrodes.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Different ways to arrange two electrodes. </div> <p>Since I’m working with POM nanoparticles, the best configuration is “coplanar”. Because POMs don’t form very continuous films: there are some pinholes in the film (see image below). The issue with these pinholes is that in a vertical architecture, the top electrode could penetrate the film and directly come into contact with the bottom electrode and shorting the device. Therefore, the coplanar configuration is the best choice for POMs. To even more optimize the device layout, the two electrodes could be coplanar, but separated by a nanogap. This would help the device to be faster and more energy-efficient.</p> <div class="col-md-6 mx-auto"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/POMFilm-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/POMFilm-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/POMFilm-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/POMFilm.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Optical microscopy image of drop-cast H<sub>3</sub>PMo<sub>12</sub>O<sub>40</sub> film, the scale bar is 10 µm. </div> <p>However, fabricating nanogap separated coplanar electrodes can be quite expensive! For example, e-beam lithography is very precise, but is also very expensive. Therefore, I used a technique called “<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41528-018-0031-3">adhesion-lithography</a>” to make my electrodes. It is compatible with large area substrates, can produce many devices quickly and efficiently, and is low-cost. The steps are shown in the image below.</p> <p>To start, the first electrode is deposited on the substrate and patterned via standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photolithography">photolithography</a>. In my case, I chose to work with aluminium (Al for short). Next, the entire substrate is dipped in a carefully chosen self-assembled monolayer (or SAM for short) molecule solution. This SAM choice is important as it must attach only to the first electrode and not the substrate. Therefore, in this case, since I work with an aluminium electrode and glass substrate, I chose octadecylphosphonic acid (ODPA for short). The ODPA molecule has a phosphonic acid head group (green in the image) that attaches to the Al electrode and a long hydrophobic tail (pink in image), which will be important later. The next step is to deposit the second electrode all over the substrate without any patterning. In my case, I use gold (or Au for short). Then, a glue is applied to the entire substrate, left to dry, and peeled off. Now is when that SAM’s hydrophobic tail is important. Since it’s only on the aluminium electrode, the gold on top of it isn’t strongly attached and can be peeled off. However, the gold on the glass substrate is strongly attached and remains on the substrate: there was no SAM in the way. The last step is to remove the SAM in order to get the nanogap separated coplanar electrodes. This can be done by simply ozone ashing the substrate, which will burn away the organic SAM molecules.</p> <div> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/ElectrodeFabrication-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/ElectrodeFabrication-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/ElectrodeFabrication-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/ElectrodeFabrication.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Adhesion-lithography process. </div> <p>This technique is compatible with different device architectures. The two electrodes can have many designs. In my work, I was simply interested in studying this combination of POM with Al and Au electrodes, so I used simple square patterned devices (see below). The first three images are a top view of the finished electrodes. The last image is a cut view of the electrodes to better show the nanogap.</p> <p>The first image shows that 81 devices can be comfortably fit on a 2x2 cm glass substrate. Each gold square is one memory device. The second image shows a zoomed-in view of a single device: each side measures 1 mm. The third image shows an even more zoomed-in view of the interface between the Al and Au electrodes: the nanogap is quite smooth and uniform. Finally, the last image is a cut view of the electrodes to better show the nanogap, which itself measured about 20 nm.</p> <div> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Electrodes_CutView-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Electrodes_CutView-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Electrodes_CutView-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Electrodes_CutView.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Finished adhesion-lithography electrodes. The two far right images are reproduced from <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41528-018-0031-3">this paper</a>. </div> <p>And there we have it! The electrodes are made, now we simply need to deposit the POMs in the nanogap, and get testing the device! I’m currently waiting on my research paper to get published, then I’ll make a new blog post about the results. So stay tuned!</p> <p>Here are some references you can check out if you want to learn more:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Electronic memory technologies</strong>: Semiconductor Memories and Systmes; Redaelli, A., Pellizzer, F., Eds.; WoodHead Publishing Series In Electronic and Optical Materials; Woodhead Publishing: Cambridge, MA, 2022.</li> <li><strong>Polyoxometalates</strong>: Pope, M. T. Heteropoly and Isopoly Oxometalates; Jørgensen, C. K., Lappert, M. F., Lippard, S. J., Margrave, J. L., Niedenzu, K., Nöth, H., Parry, R. W., Yamatera, H., Series Eds.; Inorganic Chemistry Concepts; Springer Berlin Heidelberg: Berlin, Heidelberg, 1983; Vol. 8.</li> <li><strong>Adhesion-lithography</strong>: Semple, J.; Georgiadou, D. G.; Wyatt-Moon, G.; Yoon, M.; Seitkhan, A.; Yengel, E.; Rossbauer, S.; Bottacchi, F.; McLachlan, M. A.; Bradley, D. D. C.; Anthopoulos, T. D. Large-Area Plastic Nanogap Electronics Enabled by Adhesion Lithography. npj Flex Electron 2018, 2 (1), 18. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41528-018-0031-3">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41528-018-0031-3</a>.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="PhD"/><category term="background"/><category term="polyoxometalates"/><category term="memories"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's talk about my PhD research!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A bit more about Emilie</title><link href="https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/about-emilie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A bit more about Emilie"/><published>2024-11-13T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-13T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/about-emilie</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://egerou.github.io/blog/2024/about-emilie/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to this blog post! I’d like to tell you a bit more about myself. I’m Emilie, and I just finished my PhD in electronics and material science.</p> <p>I was born in the United States of America, but grew up in Belgium. On one of the flights from the US to Belgium, when I was little kid (about 4 years old), I turned around on my seat, and chatted with the people behind me the ENTIRE flight!! Good thing they were super nice and didn’t mind. They even gave me a nickname: “piplette”, which as you probably guessed, means “chatterbox” in French. As you can see, since pretty early on, I’ve always loved meeting new people and talking to them.</p> <p>When I was a bit older, I visited the <a href="https://www.chambord.org/fr/">Château de Chambord</a> and saw <a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/How-Does-a-Double-Helix-Staircase-Work">Leonardo da Vinci’s double staircase</a>. After seeing all his other fascinating inventions, I decided I wanted to become an inventor too. A couple of years later, during a visit to the <a href="https://www.sciencemuseum.org.uk">British Science Museum</a>, I saw an exhibit on nanotechnology, and I was sold. I knew right then and there I wanted to study science as much as possible! That’s why finishing my PhD is like a dream come true: I’m a scientist now!</p> <div> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/DoubleHelixStaircase.webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/DoubleHelixStaircase.webp" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="75%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Illustration of the Château de Chambord double-helix staircase. Reproduced from <a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/How-Does-a-Double-Helix-Staircase-Work">Britannica</a>. </div> <p>But before getting there, I had to first study Chemistry at the Université Libre de Bruxelles (in Belgium). There, I learned about all the different types of Chemistry: organic, analytical, physical, theoretical, … I enjoyed my time there so much, I wanted to stay at university to keep studying. But I missed travelling a bit, so I was super happy when I got accepted into the <a href="https://master-asc.eu">Advanced Spectroscopy in Chemistry</a> internation masters program. I got the opportunity to study in France, Germany, and Poland. I learned more in depth about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectroscopy">spectroscopy</a>, which is very useful to characterize different materials. Check out this <a href="/projects/3_project_spectroscopy/">spectroscopy workshop material</a> if you’d like to learn more!</p> <p>That brings us to about now: I recently finished my PhD at the University of Southampton in the United Kingdom. During those 4 years, I studied how I could use new materials to make better electronic memories. I looked into using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyoxometalate">Polyoxometalates</a> (or POMs for short) because they have very interesting properties. For example, they can store different number of electrons which can be the different states of the memory device. For more info about my research, check out my <a href="/blog/2024/phd/">PhD Journey blog post</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Keggin_Tetrahedral.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Keggin_BallSticks.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Keggin Polyoxometalate structure: central PO<sub>4</sub> group in yellow surrounded by 12 MoO<sub>3</sub> groups in blue. </div> <p>I have a few ideas for the future, but I’m still figuring out what I want to do next. I think that becoming an outreach scientist would be great: I could make use of all my skills. I believe that the scientific and organizational skills I gained during my PhD combined with my experience in communication will help me create fun, engaging, and interesting educational content for various audiences. If you’d like to look through workshop ideas, please look through my other <a href="/blog/">blog posts</a>, or <a href="/teaching/">teaching section</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Welcome"/><category term="background"/><category term="hobbies"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's talk about my background!]]></summary></entry></feed>